googlebooksettlement.com 2013-03-30

# Google Book Settlement

  * Help Center Home
  * FAQs
  * Glossary
  * Contact Us
  * [Settlement Home  
](http://www.googlebooksettlement.com/intl/en/)

| 

**PRIVACY POLICY** Last Updated December 31, 2008

  1. _**General**_

This Privacy Policy applies to the [Google Book Search Settlement Website](http://www.googlebooksettlement.com/) (the "Settlement Website"), which has been established by Rust Consulting, Inc. (the "Settlement Administrator") to provide information about, and to receive and process claims for, the Google Book Settlement (the "Settlement"). The Settlement Administrator maintains the Settlement Website, which, in the future, will be maintained by the Book Rights Registry (the "Registry"). For purposes of this Privacy Policy, we refer to the Settlement Administrator, the Registry and Class Counsel as "we" or "us." Google Inc. is providing technical support and hosting services to us.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that you submit through the Settlement Website, on paper Claim Forms, or otherwise. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that is publicly available, that is lawfully obtained from outside sources or that you may submit to other websites or in connection with other programs, including the Google Book Search Partner Program.

**We and Google will only use your information pursuant to this Privacy Policy or as authorized by you. Restrictions on Google’s use of your information are fully described below inSection IV.**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, so long as the change is consistent with the [Settlement Agreement](http://www.googlebooksettlement.com/agreement.html). If we make any changes, we will post them on the Settlement Website with the date of revision and, if you provide an email address to us, we will send you an email notifying you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy.

We recommend that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that you are familiar with our privacy practices. If at any time you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at the email or postal addresses in the last paragraph of this Privacy Policy.

If we use a capitalized term in this Privacy Policy, that term has the same meaning as in the [Settlement Agreement](http://www.googlebooksettlement.com/agreement.html), unless we define it otherwise in this Privacy Policy.

  2. _**Information Collected**_
    1. **Personally Identifiable Information**

"Personally Identifiable Information" as used in this Privacy Policy is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you, including your name, street address, email address, telephone number, social security number, taxpayer identification number, and your computer’s unique identifier information. We collect Personally Identifiable Information in a variety of places on the Settlement Website, such as when you:

      * Sign up to receive the Notice of Class Action Settlement and other information about the Settlement;
      * Open a Registry account or edit your Registry account details;
      * Contact us through the Settlement Website to request information from us or for other purposes relating to the Settlement;
      * Claim your Books and Inserts to participate in the Settlement;
      * Manage your Books and Inserts, including Removing your Books, requesting that your Books not be digitized, excluding your Books or Inserts from Display Uses and including your Books in Display Uses; and
      * Opt out of the Settlement.
    2. **Other Information**

We may receive data sent by your browser or as a result of the Settlement Website’s use of "cookies."

When you visit the Settlement Website, we send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your computer. We use cookies for various reasons, including to enable us to recognize when you are logged in to the Settlement Website and to provide access to your account while you are logged in, to store your language preferences and to facilitate your use of the Settlement Website. You may be able to control how cookies are used by consulting your Internet browser software.

In addition, your browser may send us information, such as your requests to the Settlement Website, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language and the date and time of your request.

  3. _**Use of Information**_

We will only use or disclose your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or as authorized by you. We may use your information to administer the Settlement, including to respond to your inquiries, directions and requests regarding the Settlement, for the processing and administration of claims and payments (e.g., to send you amounts due under the Settlement), to effectuate the Settlement (including to use your content in accordance with the Settlement), and to improve our Settlement administration services. We also may use your information to communicate with you about the status of the Settlement, the uses of your Books and Inserts as provided by the Settlement or otherwise, the benefits available under the Settlement, and matters relating to the Registry.

We will not associate Personally Identifiable Information collected from you through the Settlement Website with any of your Personally Identifiable Information that we obtain from sources other than you or other than through the Settlement Website except for the uses specified by this Privacy Policy, unless such information is public or as authorized by you.

Except as provided in this Privacy Policy or as authorized by you, we will not share any of your Personally Identifiable Information with any other person. We may disclose information that you provide about your Books and Inserts so long as we do not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information. In addition, we may share information from you and others in aggregated, non-personally identifiable form with any other person, including members of the general public.

Under the Settlement Agreement, we will make publicly available whether a Book has been claimed and the identity of the claimant. If, however, you have reasonable privacy concerns, we may determine not to make your identity publicly available. Accordingly, if you claim a Book but you do not want us to make your identity public, please contact us at [privacy@rustconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@rustconsulting.com).

If you do not want Google to know your identity, then you should contact us at [privacy@rustconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@rustconsulting.com) and tell us that you want to use an alias in claiming a Book or Insert. In addition, you may use an alias on the paper Claim Form, and instruct us to provide Google and Outside Contractors only with the alias. In addition, if you published your Book or Insert under a pseudonym, then, if you so indicate to us on a paper Claim Form or by contacting us at privacy@rustconsulting.com, we will only disclose that pseudonym to Google and Outside Contractors.

When you submit a claim for a Book or Insert, your name (or alias) will be disclosed to other claimants of the same work. If another person also claims a work that you have claimed and the two claims are conflicting, we may contact you about how you and the other claimant could contact each other for purposes of resolving the dispute. We will not provide your contact information to other claimants without your express authorization.

Pursuant to the [Settlement Agreement](http://www.googlebooksettlement.com/agreement.html), we are obligated to share with Google certain information that you provide us, including your identity (or alias), a list of claimed Books and Inserts, instructions with respect to the management of Books and Inserts (including requests for Removal of Books and exclusion or inclusion of Books and Inserts) and other directions for Books and Inserts. If you direct that your Book be Removed, that information also will be disclosed to the Fully Participating Libraries. Furthermore, the public may be able to ascertain your directions regarding management of your Books or Inserts if those directions result in changes in the display or use of those Books or Inserts. We are also obligated to enable Google to confirm your contact information in a way that does not disclose your contact information to Google but does allow Google to confirm whether the contact information you provided to us is the same or different than contact information that Google otherwise obtains.

The information you provide in connection with opting out of the Settlement may be disclosed to the Court and parties to the Settlement, and the names of those persons who opt out will be listed on a publicly available attachment to the Final Judgment and Order of Dismissal.

We may also use information, or share information with third parties, when we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with legal process or otherwise satisfy any applicable law or regulation; or (b) prevent fraud or imminent harm, ensure the security of information or address technical issues.

We may use independent contractors, vendors and suppliers ("Outside Contractors"). If we use Outside Contractors to assist with the processing of your information, we may disclose your information to them or receive your information through them. Before disclosing any information to an Outside Contractor, we will, at a minimum, require that it agrees to comply with our obligations under this Privacy Policy with respect to information it receives from us or from you as our Outside Contractor.

We and our Outside Contractors may process your information on servers in the United States of America and in other countries. We may process your information on servers outside your own country.

  4. _**Google**_

Google will receive your information either (1) in its capacity as host of the Settlement Website or (2) pursuant to the Settlement Agreement.

**Google as Settlement Website Host**

When you provide information through the Settlement Website, Google, in its capacity as the host of that website, will receive your information. Google has agreed not to use or disclose (except to us) such information for any purpose, including any form of advertising, other than to effectuate the Settlement or when it has a good faith belief that use or disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with legal process or otherwise satisfy any applicable law or regulation; or (b) prevent fraud or imminent harm.

**Google as Recipient of Information Pursuant to the Settlement Agreement**

Pursuant to the Settlement Agreement we will share with Google certain information. The Settlement Agreement requires that Google maintain and keep in strict confidence any Personally Identifiable Information we provide to Google and that Google not use or disclose any such information for any purpose other than to effectuate the Settlement Agreement. The only two exceptions to these restrictions are (a) if the Personally Identifiable Information is publicly available or legally obtained by Google from other sources; or, (b) if the use or disclosure is authorized by you or the disclosure is required by law.

  5. _**Access to and Removal of Information**_

At any time, you may request access to our copy of your Personally Identifiable Information by contacting us at the email or postal addresses below. You may also modify our copy of your Personally Identifiable Information by editing your account information on the Settlement Website.

You may request that we delete your Personally Identifiable Information stored by us in electronic form. We will honor your request but we are unable to guarantee that all such information will be deleted because some residual information may remain on back-up storage and other media. Please note that deletion of some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information may affect your ability to participate in the Settlement, including your right to claim a Book or Insert.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or wish to contact us, please contact us by email at [privacy@rustconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@rustconsulting.com) or by postal mail at Settlement Administrator, c/o Rust Consulting, Inc., P.O. Box 9364, Minneapolis, MN 55440-9364.

|   
---|---|---
